a friend of mine is on trt and he is no
planning to have kids and where he lives
that's in Sagal in West Africa he cannot
get HCG so he asked me what are your
opinions on clet for fertility in mandor
already on trt yeah yeah um so so it
certainly has a lot of uh a lot of data
and a lot of literature behind it to say
that it is efficacious in uh increasing
FSH and LH synthesis um even if are on
trt um however there's there's certainly
I think if you're going to go down that
route and you can get it I would say
that because Clomid is is otherwise
known as chopine um but if you can get
En chopine because it's the zuo chopine
uh part of it that actually makes it
more efficacious there was a there was a
study in uh 2023 that looked at directly
at Clomid so chopine citrate versus en
chopine um and it was a fairly small
study it only had a about 50 guys in
each arm um but the guys on in chopine
uh rather than chopine citrate had
significantly higher FSH and LHS uh LH
synthesis so um you know if you it's
definitely something that if you can't
get HCG um is something that can be
utilized um but uh encline is much
better um and the ocular side effects um
if encline are slightly reduced compared
to chopine citrate so you can get um
some quite nasty ocular side effects so
or iish isues um if you uh if you don't
dose chopine citrate right and it's it's
worth thinking about the fact that the
the eye issues can be permanent as well
so it's it really is worth weighing up
um and there's also the consideration of
roox ofine as
well yeah so any any selective estrogen
receptor modulator is going to have the
impact on the Puchi to restart it into
to secreting those gonadotropin again
but reline is a good shout um you know
if I'd probably if I had the choice
between relox ofine and chopine citrate
I'd pick relox
ofine I didn't know how much cost
difference there is or an availability
um or if there's any availability issues
though either um but yeah